<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mainroad</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mainroad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R语言建立博客</title>
      <link>/post/r%E8%AF%AD%E8%A8%80%E5%BB%BA%E7%AB%8B%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r%E8%AF%AD%E8%A8%80%E5%BB%BA%E7%AB%8B%E5%8D%9A%E5%AE%A2/</guid>
      <description>R语言在Github上搭建博客第1步，Rstudio搭建平台第2步，gihub网站上的注册，并创建仓库第3步，本地blogdown建站第4步，提供给github建站第5步，创建博文</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>半月板的解剖</title>
      <link>/post/%E5%8D%8A%E6%9C%88%E6%9D%BF%E7%9A%84%E8%A7%A3%E5%89%96/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/%E5%8D%8A%E6%9C%88%E6%9D%BF%E7%9A%84%E8%A7%A3%E5%89%96/</guid>
      <description># **半月板知识普及系列** —— 第一章：半月板的解剖学 作者： 胡叶君 曾经，半月板被认为是“腿部肌肉起点的无功能残留物 functionless remnants of leg muscle origin”（Bland Sutton J.The ligaments of the knee joint// Ligaments,Bland Sutton J.Their Nature and Morphology,2th ed.London: Lewis,1987:32-38.），这种观点延续了很长时间，直到近现代，随着研究的不断深入，半月板的重要功能逐渐展现而被改变。 在现代化的生活中，代步车逐渐普及，使得人们的日常活动量大大降低。据说冷兵器时代人平均每天步行三万步，现在的人平均不到一万步，懒的人恐怕几千步都走不了。 这直接导致的结果是运动系统的退化，表现在膝关节就是半月板、软骨、肌肉的普遍退化，肌肉力量下降导致保护性差，半月板退化表现为其柔韧性差，容易撕裂、损伤。 半月板损伤目前是膝关节运动损伤中第一位的。 下面我们就来认识一下半月板。  本章内容： 1：半月板的解剖 2：半月板的形态 3：半月板的血供  ----- # 部位 * 膝关节半月板位于股骨髁与胫骨面之间，内外侧各一个。 * 内侧半月板覆盖60%左右的股胫关节面，而外侧半月板能覆盖90%的关节面。  形态  半月板大体呈月牙形，内侧半月板为“C”型，外侧半月板为“O”型。    从半月板的冠状切面看呈近似三角形，表现为周缘厚，内缘薄，上缘稍呈凹形，与股骨髁的凸起相吻合，下缘扁平，与胫骨平台相接。   主要血供 半月板的血供来自于膝下内侧动脉、膝下外侧动脉、膝中动脉、膝上内侧动脉（膝上外侧动脉不参与半月板血供）、膝降动脉、膝后内侧动脉和膝后外侧动脉，以上这些动脉形成紧绕半月板的周围动脉环。
 膝下内侧动脉 自后向前经胫骨内侧缘与腘肌上缘的筋膜内走向前侧，至胫骨内侧缘前下方沿内侧半月板外周走行。
 膝下外侧动脉 在距腓骨小头顶点上方，经腓侧副韧带深面，紧贴外侧半月板外周向前走行。
 膝中动脉 膝中动脉是囊内韧带最重要的血液供应来源，也是半月板前、后角的主要血供来源之一，穿过腘斜韧带进入囊内韧带、滑膜皱襞和半月板前、后角。
 总结 半月板损伤作为临床常见疾病，其解剖部位、形态结构及血运类型与半月板的功能和损伤类型密切相关，本章对后续半月板功能和损伤类型的分类提供了基础知识。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic HTML Elements</title>
      <link>/post/basic-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/basic-elements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main purpose of this article is to make sure that all basic HTML Elements are decorated with CSS so as to not miss any possible elements when creating new themes for Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>/post/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hugo is a static site engine written in Go.
It makes use of a variety of open source projects including:
 Cobra Viper J Walter Weatherman Cast  Learn more and contribute on GitHub.
Setup Some fun facts about Hugo:
 Built in Go Loosely inspired by Jekyll Primarily developed by spf13 on the train while commuting to and from Manhattan. Coded in Vim using spf13-vim  Have questions or suggestions?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Hu)go Template Primer</title>
      <link>/post/goisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/goisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo uses the excellent &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://golang.org/pkg/html/template/&#34;&gt;html/template&lt;/a&gt; library for
its template engine. It is an extremely lightweight engine that provides a very
small amount of logic. In our experience that it is just the right amount of
logic to be able to create a good static website. If you have used other
template systems from different languages or frameworks you will find a lot of
similarities in Go templates.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/hugoisforlovers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hugoisforlovers/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install Hugo Go to Hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your OS and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at Install Hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
 Clone the Hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313  Corresponding pseudo commands:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrate to Hugo from Jekyll</title>
      <link>/post/migrate-from-jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/migrate-from-jekyll/</guid>
      <description>Move static content to static Jekyll has a rule that any directory not starting with _ will be copied as-is to the _site output. Hugo keeps all static content under static. You should therefore move it all there. With Jekyll, something that looked like
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ images/ logo.png  should become
▾ &amp;lt;root&amp;gt;/ ▾ static/ ▾ images/ logo.png  Additionally, you&amp;rsquo;ll want any files that should reside at the root (such as CNAME) to be moved to static.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>